[narrator] Ash's goal is
to battle one of the world's
greatest Trainers, Leon!
Goh's goal is to catch
one of every kind of Pokémon,
including Mew!
This is the story of
their adventure-filled journey
through the world of Pokémon!
[camera shutter clicks]
[quirky music]
[Sophocles] Hey!
-Huh?
-Pika?
[Ash] Sophocles!
-[Pikachu] Pika!
-[boys chuckling]
Hi, Ash! Hi, Goh!
-Long time, no see!
-[chittering]
Pika, pika!
Sophocles! Togedemaru!
How's it going?
-Ampharos!
-[hums]
[chimes]
[Rotom Phone] Ampharos.
The Light Pokémon.
An Electric type.
The tip of Ampharos's tail
lights up,
guiding people who are lost.
Like a lighthouse,
this Pokémon is known
for leading ships to safety.
So this project
involves Ampharos, huh?
Sure does!
Now, why don't you say hi?
[shrieking]
-[all yell]
-Grookey, key!
I'm so sorry!
-It can get so flustered!
-Oh. That's why.
It's all right.
Nice to meet you, Ampharos.
[whines]
-Pika, pika.
-[Grookey gibbering]
-And this is Grookey.
-Nice to meet you, Grookey.
How's everyone in Alola?
Everyone's great.
They wanna see you again.
And Kiawe's psyched
to have another battle with Goh.
Oh, how's Raboot doing?
[snickers]
Come on out!
Cinderace! Cinde!
Meet Cinderace.
It evolved from Raboot.
That's awesome!
-You look so cool!
-Cinde.
All right, everyone!
[Sophocles] We're off
to the Mossdeep Space Center!
[Togedemaru chitters]
♪ I'll go anywhere
if I'm with you ♪
♪ Lightning strikes
or any shade of blue ♪
♪ The journey's the best part
♪ Even when the road gets hard
♪ I'll go anywhere
if I'm with you ♪
♪ With you
-[Goh] "Lighting...
-[Ash] ...The Way Home!"
[narrator]
Ash and Goh have arrived
at the Mossdeep Space Center
in the Hoenn region.
Let's see what they're up to
with Sophocles.
-Oh, wow. Cool!
-Pika.
We really appreciate
the invite, Sophocles!
-[Sophocles] No problem!
-Huh? What's that?
-Pika?
-Wait, Ash!
If you run off,
you're gonna get lost!
[Goh] I'll tell you, I never
expected that you'd be involved
in the Talonflame 2
Reentry Project!
[Sophocles] I'm pretty sure
I'm still dreaming.
Hm...
[lively music]
[Goh gasps]
[laughing]
-Oh?
-Hm?
Hi there!
Sophocles, are these the guests
you told us about?
-That's right!
-My name's Ash.
I'm Goh. Thanks so much!
I'm Ellery.
I do research here
at the Space Center.
We appreciate this opportunity
to let us watch you work.
I never would have dreamed
I'd be able to see
such a historic project
up close like this.
And it's so awesome there's a
Talonflame in outer space, too!
[squawks]
No, there's not.
It's a satellite
investigating asteroids.
Really? A satellite?
Pika?
[boys chuckle]
[muttering]
The reason why Talonflame 2
was launched here
from the Space Center
is so it can gather
valuable data
and samples from the asteroid.
Here's a recording
of the launch.
[swooshing]
[blasting]
[epic music]
[both gasp]
Incredible!
[Ellery]After the solid rocket
boosters broke away,
Talonflame 2 began its journey
toward the asteroid.
And after quite a long journey,
it finally arrived.
[whirring]
[hisses]
[Ellery]Talonflame 2 completed
its mission successfully.
Currently,
it's making its way back to us,
bringing data and samples.
And that's where
Ampharos comes in!
[Pokémon murmur]
[Sophocles] The light from
the tip of Ampharos's tail
has a specific wavelength,
so it's amplified
and sent up as a signal.
That signal
will ultimately be picked up
by Talonflame 2's sensors,
and those sensors
will allow the satellite
to safely reenter the atmosphere
of our planet
without it losing its way.
In other words, the light
emanating from Ampharos's tail
is acting kind of like
a lighthouse, right?
A lighthouse!
For the sea and outer space!
[beeping]
[Ellery]
We're also inviting children
from all over the planet
to get involved in the project,
with the hope they'll get
interested in space, too.
-[gasps]
-Would you look at all
of those kids?
[shrieks]
If only I had an Ampharos, too!
So! It's almost time.
Now, Sophocles, will you both
take your positions, please?
Of course!
Let's go, Ampharos!
[shrieking]
-[groaning]
-Pika!
-Groo...
[whimpering]
[boys groaning]
[whines]
Oh, Ampharos. Are you all okay?
I'm so sorry.
[chittering]
Whoa!
Now, what do you say
we all take our positions, okay?
[mumbles]
[electricity crackling]
-I hope that it's all right.
-Give it your best, Ampharos!
[epic music]
[man 1] Circuit complete!
[woman 1] Switching control
from Kraibe Observatory
in 17 seconds.
-Sixteen...
-Let's do this!
-...fifteen, fourteen...
-Ready, Ampharos?
...thirteen,
twelve, eleven, ten...
[Ellery]
Emitter angle at -0.2 degrees.
-Output, 80 percent.
-...seven, six...
[woman 1]Kraibe Observatory has
terminated its guidance signal.
Mossdeep Space Center
sending guidance signal.
-...one.
-And go!
[electricity crackling]
[zapping]
[Ellery] Talonflame 2
has received the signal.
Readings are nominal.
I don't get it, but it's cool.
To be this close
to the action...
Great, Ampharos!
[grunts]
-[Pokémon gasping]
-Cinde.
[electricity crackling]
-[explosion]
-Huh?
-What?
-[Pokémon chittering]
-[warbling]
-[whining]
Emergency stop!
Switch emergency control
over to Anias Observatory!
-Right!
-[beeping]
[zapping]
[Ellery] Report.
Anias Observatory signal sent.
All systems nominal.
Talonflame 2 is still on course.
[exhales deeply]
In the nick of time... Huh?
I'm wondering
if we made some sort of mistake.
-[Ampharos whines]
-[Ellery] Sophocles?
We should have the system
repaired for the next time,
so perhaps you should give
Ampharos a little rest for now.
-Okay.
-[whines]
Huh?
[Pokémon chattering]
-[Sophocles and Ampharos] Huh?
-Cin...
Huh?
Wow, Ampharos!
There was some trouble,
but your light went all the way
-to Talonflame 2!
-That's for sure!
It was really bright,
and then it went so far up!
[Goh] Don't worry,
Ellery is gonna fix the panel,
and after that,
you can do it again!
You're right. Thank you.
-Grookey!
-[laughs]
Ampharos, turn your light on.
[grunting]
[gibbering]
[both] Huh?
[Ampharos grunting]
[Goh] What's going on?
[Ash] Could it be
that it can't light up at all?
Grookey, key.
Maru?
Goh? But why?
Its light was bright
a few minutes ago.
Hm...
Maybe the shock of failing
has sent it into a slump.
Ampharos, keep calm, and
I'm sure you'll light up again.
Huh?
[Ampharos yells]
Wait. Ampharos? Ampharos!
[Ash] Who's that Pokémon?
-Pika?
-[Ampharos hums]
Pika, pika!
-[Ash] Ampharos?
-[Goh] Where are you?
[Pokémon chittering]
Nothing.
I guess
I'm useless here after all.
What do you mean?
It's because I'm not
Ampharos's real Trainer.
You mean Ampharos belongs
to someone else?
Mm-hm.
Big Mo lent Ampharos to me,
just so I could do this project.
-Big Mo?
-Yeah!
[Ash] Molayne works
at Hokulani Observatory.
He's Sophocles's cousin.
The thing is, I was determined
to join the project
and asked Big Mo for help.
So that's why he kindly lent
out Ampharos to work with me.
Ampharos was the reason
Mossdeep Space Center
called me in the first place.
I was really determined to make
this project a total success.
-[Goh] Sophocles...
-Groo?
[Sophocles] I can't do anything
to encourage Ampharos.
If this goes on,
it'll affect everyone's work.
Maybe I should take myself
off the project.
-I can't let you do that!
-Ash?
No matter what, you always
give it everything you've got.
[Ash] The reason you wanted in
was you wanna become
an astronaut, right?
Mm.
Then full speed ahead
to the end!
Yeah, he's right!
It's not over yet!
So the first thing we need
to do is find Ampharos!
-Where's Grookey?
-Huh?
-Pika?
-Cinde? Cinde.
[Goh] Now, Grookey's gone, too!
-[wind gusting]
-[leaves rustling]
[Goh]It is Grookey, after all.
It may have thought it saw
Ampharos's light and chased it.
[gibbers]
Grookey, roo. Grookey?
[raindrops dripping]
[raindrops trickling]
[Ash and Goh] Hey, Grookey?
-Ampharos?
-[Togedemaru chitters]
-[Ash] Where are you? Grookey?
-Pika, pika!
-Cinderace.
-[all] Huh?
Cinde.
-[Sophocles] Ampharos!
-[Togedemaru muttering]
Thank goodness!
And now, let's find Grookey.
The weather doesn't look good.
Hey, Togedemaru, we need light!
Togede!
-[grunting]
-[electricity crackles]
Oh, no. It's just not enough.
All right, Pikachu.
Thunderbolt, let's go!
-Pikachu!
-[electricity crackling]
Even a Thunderbolt's not enough.
We need something stronger that
gives off light for a long time.
You're right.
[Ash and Goh] Ampharos!
Please, we need your light
to find Grookey.
You'll help us find him,
won't you?
[whines]
Ampharos?
I've made a lot of mistakes,
and it makes me feel sad, too.
But I believe if you don't quit,
you can make
your dreams come true.
And even if I'm not good enough,
I'll always give it my best,
and I'd love it if you could
give it your very best, too!
[hums]
[grunting]
[warbling]
-Almost there.
-[Togedemaru mutters]
-[grunting]
-[chiming]
[hums]
Great! Way to go!
You're on your way!
[grumbling]
-[grunting]
-[zaps]
[all yelp]
Grookey.
[gibbering]
[light music]
-[Grookey shouting]
-Huh?
-Hey, Goh, over there!
-Grookey! Grookey!
-Grookey!
-[chitters]
-Grookey, key!
-Aww...
I was really worried about you,
Grookey.
-Cinde.
-[Ash chuckles]
[Ash] It really is like
a lighthouse.
Amazing!
Your tail's so bright,
it really lights up everything.
Mm...
-[Sophocles] Ampharos?
-Hm?
-[Togedemaru chittering]
-Back to the Space Center!
Hm?
[cheers]
[all whimper]
[trilling]
[Sophocles] Ellery?
Won't you please give us
another chance?
You really wanna try again?
Yes, of course!
The console's completely fixed.
-Huh?
-[both snicker]
-[boys chuckle]
-Quick, Ampharos!
-[Ampharos mutters]
-[both] Go get 'em!
[zapping]
[beeping]
-[alarm blares]
-[both] Huh?
[man 2] Emergency alert!
Talonflame 2
is off its projected course!
[Ellery] What happened?
[man 2]
It moved to avoid a meteor,
but that sudden change
left no time
for course correction!
What is he talking about?
Talonflame 2 is now off course.
[Ellery]
If something isn't done soon,
it will never be able to return.
[both gasp]
Huh?
[beeps]
Hm? What's going on?
[beeping]
We can do this! Ellery?
-Hm?
-I've got an idea!
What is it?
Right now, the light from
Kraibe Observatory can reach it.
From there, we alter the course
little by little,
while switching
between Anias and Carnahey.
[Sophocles]
Then when it's in the airspace
above Mossdeep Space Center,
we send the reentry signal,
bringing it back to base.
Hm, yes.
Your calculations do look sound.
-Let's try it out!
-Great!
Stand by
to contact all observatories!
[all] Sir!
[both] Hm...
[man 3] Kraibe is preparing
to send its signal!
[woman
2] Anias and Carnahey report
their preparations
are almost complete.
[mutters]
Here we go.
Success is our goal!
[all] Sir!
[uplifting music]
[zapping]
[whirring]
[man 4] Reentry initiated!
[woman 1] T minus one minute
until it enters
Mossdeep airspace.
Now! Sophocles! Ampharos!
Yes, sir!
-Ready, Ampharos?
-[mutters]
Send a beam of hope
all the way into space!
All right, light your light!
[grunting]
-Now, three, two, and one.
-Send it now!
-Right. Sending.
-[clicks]
[warbling]
Signal not received.
-What?
-Why not?
Are the clouds too thick
to get through?
Ampharos, more power!
[grunting]
Pikachu, let's help, all right?
-Use Thunderbolt!
-Pika!
Pikachu!
Togedemaru, Zing Zap, let's go!
Toge!
-[shrieks]
-Raichu, let's do this!
Use Nuzzle!
[grumbling]
[grunting]
[all] Go for it!
[zaps]
[man 5] Talonflame 2
has received the signal!
[woman 3] Beginning reentry!
[all] Huh? Whoa!
[calm music]
[lively music]
[all cheering]
[laughing]
Sophocles, you rock!
This is
one historic achievement!
-I guess, maybe...
-Ampharos, too!
-Cinde?
-Grookey, roo.
[Pokémon snoring]
Pikachu.
-[electricity crackles]
-[Pokémon mutter]
-[laughs]
-Sophocles?
Don't forget, I'm rooting
for you to become an astronaut.
Mm-hm. Thanks.
And I'll cheer you two on
as you reach for your goals!
-Awesome!
-Let's all go for it!
[Sophocles] See you later!
[Pokémon cheering]
[narrator] Watching Sophocles
zooming toward his dream,
our heroes have reaffirmed
their determination
to reach their dreams as well.
A brilliant light illuminates
all their paths,
as the journey continues!